MR. LIPSKÝ BONAPARTA
‫"السيد (ليبسكي بونابارتا)"‬
Ruhenheim.
‫"روهينهايم".‬
There it is.
‫ها هو ذا.‬
Stop it, Ludwig!
‫توقف يا "لودفيش"!‬
What on earth are you barking at?
‫علام تنبح؟‬
Has your bicycle broken again?
‫هل تعطلت درّاجتك مجددًا؟‬
Yes. The chain keeps coming off.
‫نعم. تستمر السلسلة في الخروج عن مكانها.‬
I got it off the trash heap, so I guess it is trash.
‫أخذتها من كومة قمامة وأرى أنها خردة.‬
It doesn't look like trash to me.
‫لا أجدها خردة.‬
When I ride it, everyone says, "Look at the trash! He's riding trash!"
‫وأنا أقودها يقول الجميع،‬ ‫"انظروا إلى الخردة. إنه يقود خردة!‬
"The trash is riding trash!"
‫حثالة يقود خردة."‬
That's not true.
‫هذا غير صحيح.‬
That's a magnificent five-speed super bicycle.
‫إنها درّاجة مذهلة بخمس سرعات.‬
Let me see if we can fix this again.
‫دعني أتفقدها لعلّي أستطيع إصلاحها مجددًا.‬
-You have a guest. -Who?
‫- أتاك ضيف.‬ ‫- من؟‬
Oh, right. He should be the one who called.
‫صحيح. لا بد أنه من اتصل.‬
Excuse me. Are you the guest with the reservation?
‫المعذرة. هل أنت الضيف الذي حجز غرفة؟‬
Yes. I'm Lunge.
‫نعم. أنا "لونغي".‬
Of course. Mr. Lunge, Welcome.
‫تفضل يا سيد "لونغي"، مرحبًا.‬
I called at the last minute, so I'm glad you have a room.
‫اتصلت متأخرًا ولذلك أسعدني أنني وجدت غرفة.‬
Not at all. We always have vacant rooms here.
‫لا عليك. دائمًا ما تكون لدينا غرف شاغرة.‬
It's still the off-season, is it?
‫إنها فترة ركود، أليس كذلك؟‬
It's always the off-season here.
‫دائمًا ما تكون فترة الركود مستمرة.‬
Our only other guests right now are that couple over there.
‫ضيفانا الوحيدان هنا حاليًا‬ ‫هما هذان الزوجان هناك.‬
He can't use his legs, so any kind of trip is quite difficult.
‫يعجز عن استخدام قدماه‬ ‫ولذلك يصعب عليه الخروج في أي رحلة.‬
I'll get his bag.
‫سأحضر حقيبته.‬
Thank you, Wim.
‫شكرًا يا "ويم".‬
-Take him to room 302. -Right.
‫- اصطحبه إلى الغرفة 302.‬ ‫- حسنًا.‬
How is the view from that room?
‫كيف هو المنظر الذي تطل عليه الغرفة؟‬
It has the best view in the hotel.
‫تطل الغرفة على أجمل منظر.‬
I'll leave your bag here.
‫سأترك حقيبتك هنا.‬
It doesn't look like trash to me either.
‫لا أراها خردة أنا أيضًا.‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
I think it's a pretty nice bicycle.
‫أجدها درّاجة رائعة.‬
Inspector Lunge of the BKA?
‫المفتش "لونغي"‬ ‫من مكتب الشرطة الجنائية الفيدرالية؟‬
What are you doing at a country substation like this?
‫ما الذي تفعله في قسم شرطة في الريف؟‬
I was wondering how many more officers for backup you could get if you needed it?
‫كنت أتساءل عن عدد من لديك من شرطيين‬ ‫إضافيين للدعم إن استدعت الحاجة إليهم.‬
More officers? For backup?
‫شرطيين إضافيين؟ للدعم؟‬
If I call the state police,
‫إن اتصلت بشرطة المدينة،‬
I can get quite a lot in just under an hour.
‫فسأتمكن من استدعاء عدد كبير‬ ‫في أقل من ساعة.‬
I doubt we'd ever need it in a backwater town like this.
‫أشك في أن نحتاج‬ ‫إلى ذلك في بلدة نائية كهذه.‬
You should check out everyone who comes into town from now on.
‫يجب أن تتحقق‬ ‫من كلّ من يدخلون البلدة من الآن فصاعدًا.‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
Before anything terrible happens.
‫قبل أن يقع أي حدث مروّع.‬
Nice! There we go! You're running well!
‫رائع! إنها تنطلق وبسرعة أيضًا!‬
Time to shift gears!
‫حان وقت تغيير السرعة!‬
Ow!
‫هذا مؤلم!‬
-What's wrong, trash? -You still riding that trash?
‫- ما الخطب يا حثالة؟‬ ‫- ألا تزال تقود تلك الخردة؟‬
What an ugly piece of junk!
‫ما أقبحها من خردة!‬
Stop! Cut it out!
‫كفى! توقفوا عن فعل هذا!‬
Trash!
‫حثالة!‬
Nice one!
‫أحسنت!‬
Are you okay?
‫هل أنت بخير؟‬
Are you alone?
‫هل أنت بمفردك؟‬
Are you traveling alone?
‫هل تسافر بمفردك؟‬
Yes.
‫نعم.‬
For work?
‫للعمل؟‬
No. On my free time.
‫لا. في وقت فراغي.‬
My! Aren't you lonely traveling alone?
‫عجبًا! ألا تشعر بالوحدة عند السفر وحدك؟‬
No. I'm used to it.
‫لا. اعتدت ذلك.‬
Do you have a family?
‫ألديك عائلة؟‬
Yes, I do. I have a daughter and grandchild.
‫نعم. لديّ ابنة وحفيدة.‬
You have a grandchild, don't you?
‫لديك حفيدة؟‬
Grandchildren are nice.
‫الأحفاد رائعون.‬
Ours is so very kind to us.
‫حفيدنا عطوف معنا للغاية.‬
Look. I just wrote a postcard to our grandchild.
‫انظر. كتبت للتو بطاقة بريدية له.‬
Letters are such a wonderful thing.
‫ما أروع الرسائل.‬
You can write things in a letter you just can't say face-to-face.
‫يمكنك أن تكتب في رسالة‬ ‫ما لا يمكنك قوله في حوار مباشر.‬
Why not write one yourself?
‫لم لا تكتب رسالة؟‬
A letter to my grandchild?
‫رسالة لحفيدتي؟‬
I wonder what I should write.
‫أتساءل عمّا يجب أن أكتبه.‬
Anything you like.
‫اكتب أيًا ما تريده.‬
If only I could draw too.
‫ليتي أجيد الرسم أيضًا.‬
Excuse me. Would it be possible to stay here for the night?
‫أرجو المعذرة.‬ ‫أثمة إمكانية للبقاء هنا الليلة؟‬
Yes, of course.
‫بالتأكيد.‬
I'm glad to hear it.
‫يسعدني سماع ذلك.‬
I was having a leisurely picnic, but then I lost my way.
‫كنت في نزهة للترفيه عن نفسي‬ ‫ولكنني ضللت الطريق.‬
When I finally made it to this town, it was so late.
‫عندما وصلت أخيرًا إلى هذه البلدة‬ ‫كان الوقت قد تأخر.‬
I'm glad you have a room.
‫يسعدني أن لديكم غرفة.‬
It seems nobody else got off in this town.
‫يبدو أنه ما من أحد آخر‬ ‫قد نزل في هذه البلدة.‬
A gunshot?
‫صوت طلق ناري؟‬
It didn't sound like a gunshot to me.
‫لا أجده صوت طلق ناري.‬
No, that sounded like a gunshot.
‫بلى، إنه صوت طلق ناري.‬
Nobody in this town owns a gun.
‫ما من أحد هنا معه مسدس في هذه البلدة.‬
The only one who probably does is that drunk who lives behind us.
‫الوحيد الذي قد يكون لديه مسدس‬ ‫هو ذاك السكّير الذي يقيم خلفنا.‬
It would've been a lot louder if it were behind us.
‫كان ليصبح الصوت أعلى بكثير‬ ‫إن صدر من خلفنا.‬
Besides, that alcoholic couldn't hit a thing.
‫كما أن ذلك السكّير‬ ‫ما كان ليتمكن من إصابة أي هدف.‬
Oh, darn it all! "Couldn't hit"?
‫سحقًا! ما كان ليصيب هدفه؟‬
Quit saying things like that! No wonder I always lose!
‫كفّ عن قول كلام من هذا القبيل!‬ ‫لا عجب في أنني أخسر دائمًا.‬
Darn it all!
‫سحقًا!‬
Shut up! It's not my fault! Give up those stupid lottery tickets!
‫اصمتي! إنها ليست غلطتي!‬ ‫دعك من بطاقات اليانصيب السخيفة تلك!‬
Ludwig!
‫"لودفيش"!‬
I can't find my Ludwig anywhere!
‫لا أجد "لودفيش" في أي مكان!‬
You heard that gunshot earlier, didn't you?
‫سمعت صوت الطلق الناري منذ قليل، أليس كذلك؟‬
Do you think it was my dear Ludwig? Was he shot?
‫أتظن أن عزيزي "لودفيش" هو من أُصيب؟‬
Please calm down, Mrs. Hillman.
‫اهدئي من فضلك يا سيدة "هيلمان".‬
There was no gunshot. Just calm down.
‫ما من طلق ناري قد أُطلق. اهدئي.‬
Is there something wrong?
‫أمن خطب ما؟‬
This woman's dog has gone missing.
‫كلب هذه المرأة مفقود.‬
That's worrying.
‫إنه لأمر يستدعي القلق.‬
Anyway, I'll tell the police.
‫سأخبر الشرطة.‬
I already told the police!
‫سبق أن أخبرتهم!‬
But that man is useless!
‫لكن ذلك الرجل عديم النفع!‬
He's so undependable for a police officer!
‫إنه شرطي لا يُعتمد عليه!‬
It doesn't help that he hates dogs!
‫كراهيته للكلاب لن تفيدنا.‬
How about I look for him?
‫ما رأيك في أن أبحث عنه؟‬
Can you do that, Mr. Neumaier?
‫أيمكنك فعل ذلك يا سيد "نويماير"؟‬
Sure. I'm going for a stroll around town, so I'll look while I'm out.
‫بالتأكيد. سأتمشى في البلدة‬ ‫وسأبحث عنه في أثناء ذلك.‬
Yes, I know Mrs. Hillman's dog.
‫نعم، أعرف كلب السيدة "هيلمان".‬
It's that dumb dog that never stops barking, right?
‫إنه ذلك الكلب الغبي الذي لا يكفّ عن النباح.‬
It's gone missing. Have you seen it?
‫إنه مفقود، فهل رأيته؟‬
No, I haven't.
‫لا، لم أره.‬
I see. Thanks anyway.
‫حسنًا. شكرًا على أي حال.‬
One more thing. Have you seen any odd strangers in this town lately?
‫ثمة أمر آخر. هل رأيت أي شخص غريب ومريب‬ ‫في البلدة مؤخرًا؟‬
Yes, I have.
‫بلى، رأيت.‬
Really?
‫حقًا؟‬
You.
‫أنت.‬
A dog?
‫كلب؟‬
I thought you were here for a room.
‫حسبتك أتيت لحجز غرفة.‬
I'm sorry. I'm already staying at the Versteck Hotel.
‫أنا آسف. أنا أقيم في فندق "فيرستك".‬
That darn place steals all the visitors.
‫ذلك المكان اللعين يسرق كل الزوّار.‬
So I guess that means you don't have any guests here now.
‫أفترض بذلك أنه ما ضيوف لديك حاليًا.‬
No, I don't! It's as quiet as a cemetery here.
‫لا، ما من ضيوف لديّ.‬ ‫المكان أشبه بالمقابر هنا.‬
So I'd know in an instant if that noisy dog was anywhere near here.
‫لذلك كنت لأعرف فورًا‬ ‫إن اقترب ذلك الكلب المزعج من هنا.‬
Did you hear it barking today?
‫هل سمعت نباحه اليوم؟‬
No, I didn't.
‫لا، لم أسمعه.‬
Earlier, there was that gunshot, right?
‫أُطلق في وقت سابق طلق ناري، أليس كذلك؟‬
I bet some maniac shot and killed it because it was being too damn noisy.
‫أراهن على أن ثمة معتوه ما قد أطلق عليه‬ ‫النار وقتله بسبب الصخب الذي يحدثه.‬
Hello… Mister?
‫مرحبًا يا سيدي.‬
I'm Lunge, Mr. Neumaier.
‫أنا "لونغي" يا سيد "نويماير".‬
Right. Mr. Lunge. Where are you headed?
‫صحيح، السيد "لونغي". إلى أين تتجه؟‬
I'm looking for that dog.
‫أبحث عن ذلك الكلب.‬
I see. Have you gotten any leads?
‫حسنًا. هل توصلت إلى أي أثر؟‬
No.
‫لا.‬
Then I guess we'd better keep looking.
‫أرى إذًا أنه يُستحسن بنا الاستمرار في البحث.‬
Liquor, dammit! Get me some liquor!
‫الخمر، عليك اللعنة!‬ ‫أحضر لي القليل من الخمر.‬
No, Dad! You shouldn't drink!
‫لا يا أبي! يجب ألّا تشرب!‬
Get out there and buy me some liquor, goddammit!
‫اخرج واشتر لي القليل من الخمر!‬
I don't have any money!
‫ليس معيّ مال!‬
You have the money you made at your damn job!
‫معك مال جنيته من عملك اللعين!‬
I guess maybe I can get one bottle.
‫أظن أنه يمكنني شراء زجاجة.‬
Wim.
‫"ويم".‬
Don't use it for that. That's money that you earned yourself.
‫لا تنفقه في ذلك. هذا مال كسبته بمجهودك.‬
You got beaten up pretty badly again today.
‫أرى أنك ضُربت بشدة اليوم أيضًا.‬
Come on now to my hotel.
‫تعال معي إلى الفندق.‬
MÜLLER GROCERY STORE
‫"(مولر)، متجر للمواد الغذائية"‬
This is great!
‫كم هي لذيذة!‬
Not many people around here enjoy them like you do.
‫ما من كثيرين يحبونها مثلك.‬
Is that right? But this is just so darn good.
‫حقًا؟ لكنها شهية للغاية.‬
Really? It's just a sausage.
‫حقًا؟ إنها مجرد نقانق.‬
This is the face I make when I eat good food.
‫هذا ما يظهر على وجهي‬ ‫عندما أتناول طعامًا شهيًا.‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
This is a nice town. It's quiet and has delicious food.
‫إنها بلدة جميلة. إنها هادئة وطعامها لذيذ.‬
Do you think so?
‫أتظن هذا حقًا؟‬
I want to get out of this dull town as soon as I can.
‫أريد أن أخرج من هذه البلدة المملة‬ ‫في أسرع وقت ممكن.‬
I wish I can meet some handsome guy who would take me away from here.
‫أتمنى أن أقابل رجلًا وسيمًا‬ ‫يأخذني بعيدًا عن هنا.‬
Have any handsome guys been around lately?
‫ألم يزر البلدة أي شخص وسيم مؤخرًا؟‬
Not at all.
‫على الإطلاق.‬
I get the same customers every darn day. I'm sick of it.
‫أستقبل الزبائن ذاتهم يوميًا. سئمت ذلك.‬
By the way, about that dog…
‫بالمناسبة، بشأن ذلك الكلب…‬
Right. I've taken that dog for a walk myself.
‫صحيح. أخرجت ذلك الكلب في نزهة بنفسي.‬
You have?
‫حقًا؟‬
When Mrs. Hillman was in bed with a cold,
‫عندما كانت السيدة "هيلمان" مصابة بالزكام،‬
I took him for a walk for her.
‫أخرجته في نزهة من أجلها.‬
When I gave him one of our deli's Eisbein bones,
‫عندما أعطيته عظمة مفصل،‬
he wouldn't let go of it!
‫ما كان يريد تركها!‬
He pulled it out of my hand with incredible strength and ran off!
‫شدّها من يدي بقوة رهيبة وهرب بها.‬
Where did he go then?
‫إلى أين ذهب؟‬
Inspector Lunge.
‫حضرة المفتش "لونغي".‬
It's just as you've said, something terrible did happen.
‫ثمة أمر مريع قد طرأ كما توقعت تمامًا.‬
That dog, it's gone missing.
‫ذلك الكلب فُقد.‬
Did you hear that gunshot?
‫هل سمعت ذلك الطلق الناري؟‬
Oh, that. That wasn't a gunshot.
‫بشأن ذلك. لم يكن طلقًا ناريًا.‬
A car broke down on the state highway.
‫تعطلت سيارة على الطريق السريع.‬
I bet it was just that car backfiring.
‫أنا متأكد من أنه صوت صدر عن تلك السيارة.‬
We never hear gunshots in this town.
‫لا نسمع طلقات نارية في البلدة هنا أبدًا.‬
See you.
‫أراك لاحقًا.‬
You don't want to scare me like that, you know.
‫ما كان ليرضيك أن تخيفني هكذا.‬
There he is.
‫وجدته.‬
Ludwig.
‫"لودفيش".‬
You sure have caused a lot of trouble.
‫لقد تسببت بالكثير من المتاعب.‬
You must have remembered you buried that bone here.
‫لا بد أنك تذكرت دفنك لتلك العظمة هنا.‬
Hello, Mr. Lunge.
‫مرحبًا يا سيد "لونغي".‬
I guess we both arrived at the same place from different leads.
‫أرى أننا وصلنا إلى المكان ذاته‬ ‫بتتبع أثرين مختلفين.‬
What are you doing in this town?
‫ما الذي تفعله في هذه البلدة؟‬
I could ask you the same thing. You're a police detective, right?
‫يمكنني أن أطرح عليك السؤال نفسه.‬ ‫أنت محقق لدى الشرطة، أليس كذلك؟‬
I could kind of tell.
‫يمكنني تبيّن ذلك.‬
You have the aura of a detective.
‫لديك هالة محقق.‬
I'm on vacation.
‫أنا في أجازة.‬
From that look in your eyes, it sure doesn't seem like you're on vacation.
‫أرى في عينيك أنك لست في أجازة.‬
I was just in Prague not long ago.
‫كنت في "براغ" من فترة ليست طويلة.‬
I got info there on a certain person involved in a certain case.
‫تلقيت معلومة عن شخص متورط في قضية ما.‬
He's a tall man carrying a large bag.
‫شخص طويل يحمل حقيبة كبيرة.‬
He's friendly and has a gentle smile.
‫وهو ودود وله ابتسامة رقيقة.‬
His hair color is…
‫لون شعره…‬
You're an exact match with the information I have on the man,
‫ثمة تطابق تام بينك وبين المعلومات‬ ‫التي لديّ عن هذا الشخص،‬
Mr. Neumaier.
‫يا سيد "نويماير".‬
I mean, Mr. Grimmer.
‫بل يا سيد "غريمر".‬
What have you come to this town for?
‫ما سبب قدومك إلى هذه البلدة؟‬
It does seem like you and I
‫يبدو أنني أنا وأنت‬
both arrived at the same place through different leads.
‫قد وصلنا إلى المكان نفسه‬ ‫بتقفي أثرين مختلفين.‬
Isn't that right?
‫أليس كذلك؟‬
Do you think it can be stopped?
‫أتظن أنه بالإمكان إيقافها؟‬
The horrible massacre that will happen in this town.
‫المجزرة المروّعة التي ستقع في هذه البلدة.‬
Are you checking the lottery numbers again?
‫هل تتحققين من أرقام اليانصيب مجددًا؟‬
Your husband's about to go to work to pay for that.
‫سيخرج زوجك للعمل لدفع ثمنها.‬
You talk big, but you earn a pittance.
‫تتبجح بكلامك ولا تتقاضى إلا الفتات.‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
We have no future unless we win the lottery.
‫لن يكون لنا أي مستقبل إن لم نفز باليانصيب.‬
If you don't like it, then earn more.
‫إن لم يعجبك ذلك، فاكسب المزيد.‬
Honey!
‫عزيزي.‬
Oh, what is it now?
‫ما الأمر الآن؟‬
What is it, dammit?
‫ما الأمر؟‬
We won!
‫فزنا!‬
Won what?
‫فزنا بماذا؟‬
The lottery!
‫اليانصيب!‬
Give it back!
‫أعيدوها!‬
What did you do with my bicycle?
‫ماذا فعلتم بدرّاجتي؟‬
Get lost!
‫ابتعد!‬
We don't know about any bicycles.
‫لا نعرف شيئًا عن أي درّاجة.‬
But we did toss out some trash.
‫لكن ثمة خردة رميناها.‬
Did you toss it out?
‫رميتم الدرّاجة؟‬
We tossed it into the vampire's house in the west hills.
‫رميناها عند بيت مصاص الدماء‬ ‫عند التلال الغربية.‬
The vampire…
‫مصاص الدماء…‬
If you want it back, go get it yourself.
‫إن أردت استعادتها، فاستعدها بنفسك.‬
But don't blame us if you don't come back.
‫ولكن لا تلمنا إن لم تعد.‬
You piece of trash!
‫أيها الحثالة.‬
Honey…
‫عزيزي…‬
Did anyone come by?
‫هل أتى أحد؟‬
No…
‫لا…‬
Make sure you chain the door.
‫احرصي أن على تقفلي الباب بالسلسلة.‬
So…
‫إذًا…‬
Yes?
‫نعم؟‬
Are you sure the numbers are a match?
‫أمتأكدة من تطابق الأرقام؟‬
I've checked several times.
‫تفقدتها عدة مرات.‬
We… did win.
‫نحن قد فزنا.‬
Twenty million marks, huh?
‫20 مليون مارك؟‬
What will we do, honey?
‫ماذا سنفعل يا عزيزي؟‬
I went to the next town.
‫ذهبت إلى البلدة المجاورة.‬
Honey, what are these?
‫ما هذه يا عزيزي؟‬
Just a precaution.
‫تحسبًا فقط.‬
With all that money, it's too dangerous to be unarmed.
‫من الخطر للغاية ألا نكون مسلحين‬ ‫وهذا المبلغ معنا.‬
But as long as nobody finds out, we won't need to use these.
‫لكن ما دام لم يعرف أحد،‬ ‫فلن نضطر إلى استخدامها.‬
But…
‫لكن…‬
What is it now?
‫ما المشكلة الآن؟‬
There isn't anyone who knows what numbers you chose, is there?
‫ما من أحد يعرف الأرقام التي اخترتها،‬ ‫أليس كذلك؟‬
When I bought that lottery ticket…
‫عندما اشتريت بطاقة اليانصيب هذه…‬
The usual.
‫المعتادة.‬
Here you go.
‫تفضّلي.‬
You never seem to win, do you, Mrs. Heinich?
‫يبدو أنك لا تفوزين مطلقًا يا سيدة "هينيش"؟‬
Hello, Mr. Conrad.
‫مرحبًا يا سيد "كونراد".‬
Your husband complains about your obsession with the lottery.
‫يشتكي زوجك من هوسك باليانصيب.‬
Why don't you try using my birthday? March 2, 1945.
‫لم لا تجرّبين استخدام عيد ميلادي؟‬ ‫2 مارس 1945.‬
Those numbers won quite a bit.
‫فازت هذه الأرقام ببعض المكاسب.‬
I've won two long shots at the horse races with them.
‫فزت في محاولتين ضعُفت احتمالية فوزهما‬ ‫في سباقات الخيل.‬
Yeah, yeah. Maybe sometime.
‫حسنًا. قد أجرّبها ذات مرة.‬
Don't tell me… you used the birthday of that Conrad?
‫لا تقولي إنك استخدمت‬ ‫عيد ميلاد "كونراد" ذاك؟‬
Yes…
‫بلى…‬
If he sees the numbers in the paper…
‫إن رأى الأرقام في الجريدة…‬
But he doesn't know if you bet on those numbers, right?
‫لكنه لا يعرف‬ ‫ما إن كنت راهنت بهذه الأرقام، صحيح؟‬
I don't know.
‫لا أعرف.‬
Rumors could be spreading through town by now--
‫قد تكون الشائعات قد انتشرت في البلدة…‬
Come to think of it…
‫ذكّرني ذلك…‬
What is it?
‫ماذا؟‬
On my way home just now,
‫عندما كنت في طريقي إلى البيت،‬
when I stopped by the store for cigarettes…
‫مررت على المتجر لشراء سجائر…‬
The girl from the sausage shop was staring at me.
‫فتاة متجر النقانق كان تحدّق إليّ.‬
That's right! The same thing happened to me!
‫صحيح! حدث الأمر ذاته معي.‬
When I took out the trash just now,
‫بينما كنت أخرج القمامة منذ قليل،‬
the drunk out back was there staring at me!
‫السكّير الذي يسكن خلفنا كان يحدّق إليّ!‬
If that alcoholic hears about us winning all this money, he might--
‫إن سمع ذلك السكّير بأننا كسبنا‬ ‫هذا المبلغ من المال، فقد…‬
-Calm down! -But!
‫- اهدئي!‬ ‫- لكن…‬
Listen. We'll just have to protect ourselves.
‫اسمعي. سيتوجب علينا أن نحمي أنفسنا.‬
The vampire's house…
‫بيت مصاص الدماء…‬
It's dead…
‫إنها ميتة…‬
Someone is here.
‫ثمة أحد هنا.‬
Judging from the look of things…
‫بالنظر إلى ما تبدو عليه الأمور…‬
He hasn't been here recently.
‫لم يأت إلى هنا مؤخرًا.‬
None of them are finished.
‫لم تُنه أي واحدة.‬
Did he stop painting?
‫هل توقف عن الرسم؟‬
Or maybe he couldn't paint anymore.
‫أم ما عاد بوسعه أن يرسم؟‬
Well, if it isn't Wim!
‫عجبًا، إنه "ويم"!‬
Mr. Neumaier. Mr. Lunge.
‫سيد "نويماير" وسيد "لونغي".‬
What are you doing here?
‫ما الذي تفعله هنا؟‬
My bicycle…
‫درّاجتي…‬
My friends said they tossed out my bicycle here.
‫قال أصدقائي إنهم رموها هنا.‬
Your friends pulled a trick on you?
‫هل خدعوك؟‬
Your bicycle was in the bushes at the bottom of the trail up here.
‫كانت درّاجتك في الشجيرات‬ ‫في نهاية الطريق المؤدي إلى هنا.‬
Anyway…
‫بأي حال…‬
It looks like that cat was killed with a submachine gun.
‫يبدو أن القطة قُتلت بمدفع آلي.‬
Are they already here?
‫هل وصلوا؟‬
Yes. They're very close.
‫نعم. إنهم قريبون جدًا.‬
Look at this.
‫انظر إلى هذه.‬
-A drawing of twins. -Correct.
‫- رسمة لتوأم.‬ ‫- صحيح.‬
This one is too.
‫هذه أيضًا.‬
And this one.
‫وهذه.‬
-There must be about ten. -What?
‫- لا بد أنهما في قرابة العاشرة.‬ ‫- ماذا؟‬
When I got the Tenma case, those twins were about ten years old.
‫عندما توليت قضية "تينما"،‬ ‫كان التوأم في قرابة العاشرة من العمر.‬
It looks like it was drawn about then.
‫يبدو أنها رُسمت في تلك الفترة.‬
How many times has he drawn the same picture?
‫كم مرة رسم الرسمة ذاتها؟‬
No matter how many times he draws them, he's not satisfied.
‫مهما رسم منها، فإنه لا يرضى.‬
Good grief.
‫ويلاه.‬
Looks like there will be lots of creeping vines this year.
‫يبدو أن النبات المتسلّق‬ ‫سيكون كثيرًا هذا العام.‬
We might not be getting many lingonberries this year.
‫قد لا نحظى بالكثير من عنب الثور هذا العام.‬
Say, I've never seen you around here before.
‫لم أرك هنا من قبل.‬